So here you can see I've set up all the different parts we will need for a server,
这是创建一个服务器需要的代码
and then right down here is the server code that we just saw.
这里是我们刚才编写的代码
Now, one of the things that's different about a server,
和你在浏览器中常见的日志信息不同
is that you're probably used to seeing your log messages in the browser itself.
编写服务器端代码时
But when you're doing server-side code,
日志信息
you'll get all the messages in the terminal. Like this.
打印在终端
I'm going to tell node to run my server file,
在终端执行 node 文件名
by saying node and then the name of my file.
运行代码
Awesome. So let's actually use
啊哦 刚好借此机会学习一下怎么调试
this as a teaching moment to understand what I was doing wrong.
看看我哪里做错了
I realized and it's a common mistake that you should
在错误的目录执行命令
always double-check what directory you're in.
是常见的错误之一 你要好好检查一下当前所处目录
So I was in the directory dsb_go which is one level up from where I want to be,
我现在在 dsb_go 目录 是我想要执行命令的上一级目录
which is inside of my sample project which actually has the file that I'm looking for.
而代码在 UdacitySampleProject 目录
So the issue was that I was telling node to look for
问题清楚了 我让 Node 在错误的路径下查找文件
a file that they didn't know existed.
当然不存在了
So if I go into the right directory,
让我们进入正确的目录
which is the udacitySampleProject,
UdacitySampleProject
and then I tell node to run my file,
然后运行代码
we get the feedback we're looking for which is that the server is running,
终于得到了预期的反馈 服务器跑起来了
and it tells us that it's running on localhost: 8000.
运行在 localhost:8000
So just to review,
复习一下
an Express Server is created using the listen method,
使用 listen 方法创建 Express 服务器
which takes two arguments: a port to run
该方法有两个参数
the server on and a callback function to execute.
一个服务器上的端口和一个待执行的回调函数
Let's walk through this code quickly just so that we all have an idea of what's going on.
让我们快速浏览一遍代码 弄清楚究竟发生了什么
On line two, we're requiring Express which
第二行引入 Express
we would have already installed from the command line as we've seen.
之前已经在命令行安装好了
Then we create an instance of our app here with Express,
然后创建一个实例
and then come the dependencies,
接着是需要的依赖
the middleware as we talked about,
就是之前提到的中间件 body-parser
bodyParser so that we can parse our data.
用它解析数据
Here we use the use method,
这里使用 use 方法
just to tell bodyParser exactly how we want our data to be dealt with.
告诉 body-parser 处理的数据格式
So we're going to mostly want JSON.
多数情况下都是 JSON
Here, similar to the bodyParser package,
和 body-parser 类似
we're requiring a package we've installed on the command line which is called const.
引入另外一个在命令行中安装的包 cors
Const is a package that lets the browser and server
cors 能让浏览器和服务器免受安全限制
talk to each other without any security interruptions.
自由通信
On line 18, we use our use method again,
在第 18 行又用到了 use 方法
and this time, we're pointing our app to the folder that we want them to look at.
这次将应用指向了一个可以访问的目录
We'll cover this in more detail later.
稍后我们会详细介绍
But this one simple line of code is what allows us to write
这么简单的一样代码
server-side code that can then connect to
就可以把服务器端代码和客户端代码
client-side code which would be in a folder called demo.
关联起来 让客户端访问 demo 目录
Then we get to our beautiful server which we've gone over, we set our port,
最后来到可爱的服务器 设置端口
we call the listen method,
调用 listen 方法
we pass it to our callback function,
传入回调函数
we got ourselves a server.
我们有了一个 Web 服务器